<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-09-13T23:57:31+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Zeyi Liu</title><subtitle>Personal Acadamic Homepage</subtitle><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><entry><title type="html">IEEE TNNLS [DSLS]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/03/LiuZY07/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE TNNLS [DSLS]" /><published>2023-07-03T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-07-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/03/LiuZY07</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/03/LiuZY07/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dynamic Submodular-based Learning Strategy in Imbalanced Drifting Streams for Real-time Safety Assessment in Nonstationary Environments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/Samlzy/pics/raw/Samlzy-patch-1/LiuZY07.png&quot; alt=&quot;GA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Dynamic submodular-based learning strategy in imbalanced drifting streams for real-time safety assessment in nonstationary environments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: The design of real-time safety assessment approaches in nonstationary environments is meaningful to reduce the possibility of significant losses. However, several challenging problems are needed to be well considered. The performance of existing approaches will be negatively affected in the settings of imbalanced drifting streams. In this case, the model design with the incremental update should also be explored. Furthermore, the query strategy should also be well designed. This paper investigates a dynamic submodular-based learning strategy to address such issues. Specifically, an efficient incremental update procedure is designed with the structure of the broad learning system, which is beneficial to the detection of concept drift. Furthermore, a novel dynamic submodular-based annotation with activation interval strategy is proposed to select valuable samples in imbalanced drifting streams. The lower bound of annotation value is also proven theoretically with a novel drift adaption mechanism. Numerous experiments are conducted with the realistic data of JiaoLong deep-sea manned submersible. The experimental results show that the proposed approach can achieve better assessment accuracy than typical existing approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: In Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 14.255&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCF Rank (中国计算机学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Z. Liu and X. He, &quot;Dynamic Submodular-Based Learning Strategy in Imbalanced Drifting Streams for Real-Time Safety Assessment in Nonstationary Environments,&quot; in IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems, doi: 10.1109/TNNLS.2023.3294788.

@ARTICLE{10195233,
  author={Liu, Zeyi and He, Xiao},
  journal={IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems}, 
  title={Dynamic Submodular-Based Learning Strategy in Imbalanced Drifting Streams for Real-Time Safety Assessment in Nonstationary Environments}, 
  year={2023},
  volume={},
  number={},
  pages={1-14},
  doi={10.1109/TNNLS.2023.3294788}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="Journal," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Dynamic Submodular-based Learning Strategy in Imbalanced Drifting Streams for Real-time Safety Assessment in Nonstationary Environments</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Preprint — [EEPL]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/01/LiuZY09/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preprint — [EEPL]" /><published>2023-07-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/01/LiuZY09</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/01/LiuZY09/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evidential Ensemble Preference-guided Learning Approach for Real-time Multi-mode Fault Diagnosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidential ensemble preference-guided learning approach for real-time multi-mode fault diagnosis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Operational changes in industrial production can alter system operating modes, which complicates real-time fault diagnosis by affecting sensor data and fault characteristics. Additionally, fault diagnosis tasks encounter the challenge of fault feature drift, which causes a decline in the performance of previously trained models on new data. This paper presents a novel approach for real-time multi-mode fault diagnosis called the evidential ensemble preference-guided approach to tackle these issues. During the offline stage, we extract ensemble preferences of fault information across different operating modes based on the structure of broad learning system. Subsequently, a parameter iterative update rule is developed that utilizes an evidence reasoning technique to emphasize the preferences during the online stage. The effectiveness of our approach is evaluated by constructing a real-time multi-mode fault diagnosis dataset using the Tennessee Eastman process and conducting multiple experiments. The results demonstrate that our proposed approach effectively identifies operating modes and diagnoses faults simultaneously, surpassing existing advanced methods.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="preprint," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Evidential Ensemble Preference-guided Learning Approach for Real-time Multi-mode Fault Diagnosis</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Preprint — [OMIS-RVFL]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/23/HanPY02/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preprint — [OMIS-RVFL]" /><published>2023-06-23T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-06-23T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/23/HanPY02</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/23/HanPY02/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online Minority-cluster Informed Semi-supervised Random Vector Functional Link Network Approach for Multi-mode Fault Diagnosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Online minority-cluster informed semi-supervised random vector functional link network approach for multi-mode fault diagnosis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Industrial real-time fault diagnosis is vital to ensure efficient and safe production. In the literature, existing methods usually do not systematically consider some realistic constraints under multi-mode scenarios, such as high labeling costs and sample imbalance. In this paper, an online minority-cluster informed semi-supervised random vector functional link network approach, termed OMIS-RVFL, is proposed to cope with the above issue. Specifically, the pseudo-labeling technique is introduced to mitigate the negative impact of the imbalanced data stream. On this basis, the minority-cluster informed approach is designed to increase the linear separability of transition samples and achieve better identification of minority samples by performing dimensionality reduction and minority prioritization. Several experiments with the Tennessee Eastman process are conducted to verify the practicality of OMIS-RVFL. The results demonstrate that the proposed method outperforms the existing state-of-the-art approaches regarding multi-mode fault diagnosis performance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="preprint," /><category term="Rank-2" /><summary type="html">Online Minority-cluster Informed Semi-supervised Random Vector Functional Link Network Approach for Multi-mode Fault Diagnosis</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Preprint — [CADM+]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/03/HuSQ01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preprint — [CADM+]" /><published>2023-06-03T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-06-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/03/HuSQ01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/03/HuSQ01/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CADM+: Confusion-based Learning Framework with Drift Detection and Adaptation for Chunk-level Real-time Safety Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: CADM+: confusion-based learning framework with drift detection and adaptation for chunk-level real-time safety assessment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time safety assessment (RTSA) has become a topic of great interest in recent years due to the complex and rapidly changing nature of data streams. To address this issue, a novel chunk-level and confusion-based learning framework with drift detection and adaptation, called CADM+, is proposed in this paper. When drift occurs, the model is updated with uncertain samples, which may cause confusion between existing and new concepts, resulting in performance differences. To measure the degree of conceptual confusion in the model, cosine similarity is used. Furthermore, the change of standard deviation within a fixed-size cosine similarity window is introduced as an indicator for drift detection. Theoretical demonstrations show the asymptotic increasing and approximate independence of cosine similarity and the change of standard deviation with the number of trained samples, respectively. Finally, extreme value theory is applied to determine the threshold of judging drifts. The proposed framework is evaluated on the realistic data of JiaoLong deep-sea manned submersible and several benchmark datasets, which demonstrates its effectiveness. Experimental results also prove that the proposed framework is more suitable for RTSA tasks compared to state-of-the-art algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="preprint," /><category term="Rank-2" /><summary type="html">CADM+: Confusion-based Learning Framework with Drift Detection and Adaptation for Chunk-level Real-time Safety Assessment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CPCC 2023 [IBLS-ER]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/28/LiC-CPCC/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CPCC 2023 [IBLS-ER]" /><published>2023-04-28T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-04-28T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/28/LiC-CPCC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/28/LiC-CPCC/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Evidential Real-Time Multi-Mode Fault Diagnosis Approach Based on Broad Learning System&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/Samlzy/pics/raw/Samlzy-patch-1/LiC-C-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;GA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: An evidential real-time multi-mode fault diagnosis approach based on broad learning system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;The 34th Chinese Process Control Conference, 2023&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Fault diagnosis is a crucial area of research in the industry due to diverse operating conditions that exhibit non-Gaussian, multi-mode, and center-drift characteristics. Currently, data-driven approaches are the main focus in the field, but they pose challenges for continuous fault classification and parameter updates of fault classifiers, particularly in multiple operating modes and real-time settings. Therefore, a pressing issue is to achieve real-time multi-mode fault diagnosis for industrial systems. To address this problem, this paper proposes a novel approach that utilizes an evidence reasoning (ER) algorithm to fuse information and merge outputs from different base classifiers. These base classifiers are developed using a broad learning system (BLS) to improve good fault diagnosis performance. Moreover, in this approach, the pseudo-label learning method is employed to update model parameters in real-time. To demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed approach, we perform experiments using the multi-mode Tennessee Eastman process dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Accept&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="Conference," /><category term="Rank-2" /><summary type="html">An Evidential Real-Time Multi-Mode Fault Diagnosis Approach Based on Broad Learning System</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SAFEPROCESS-2023 [RTSA-Survey]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/15/LiuZYC01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SAFEPROCESS-2023 [RTSA-Survey]" /><published>2023-04-15T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-04-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/15/LiuZYC01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/15/LiuZYC01/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Real-time Safety Assessment of Dynamic Systems in Non-stationary Environments: A Review of Methods and Techniques&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/Samlzy/pics/raw/Samlzy-patch-1/LiuZY-C-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;GA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time safety assessment of dynamic systems in non-stationary environments: a review of methods and techniques&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;CAA Symposium on Fault Detection, Supervision, and Safety for Technical Processes (SAFEPROCESS), 2023&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time safety assessment (RTSA) of dynamic systems is a critical task that has significant implications for various fields such as industrial and transportation applications, especially in non-stationary environments. However, the absence of a comprehensive review of real-time safety assessment methods in non-stationary environments impedes the progress and refinement of related methods. In this paper, a review of methods and techniques for RTSA tasks in non-stationary environments is provided. Specifically, the background and significance of RTSA approaches in non-stationary environments are firstly highlighted. We then present a problem description that covers the definition, classification, and main challenges. We review recent developments in related technologies such as online active learning, online semi-supervised learning, online transfer learning, and online anomaly detection. Finally, we discuss future outlooks and potential directions for further research. Our review aims to provide a comprehensive and up-to-date overview of real-time safety assessment methods in non-stationary environments, which can serve as a valuable resource for researchers and practitioners in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Accept&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compendex&lt;/strong&gt;: EI Compendex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="Conference," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Real-time Safety Assessment of Dynamic Systems in Non-stationary Environments: A Review of Methods and Techniques</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE TIM [Ivrr-PPG]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/13/XuM-01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE TIM [Ivrr-PPG]" /><published>2023-04-13T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-04-13T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/13/XuM-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/13/XuM-01/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ivrr-PPG: An Illumination Variation Robust Remote-PPG Algorithm for Monitoring Heart Rate of Drivers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/Samlzy/pics/raw/Samlzy-patch-1/XuM01-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;GA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/Samlzy/pics/raw/Samlzy-patch-1/XuM01-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;GA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Ivrr-PPG: an illumination variation robust remote-PPG algorithm for monitoring heart rate of drivers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Heart rate can be accurately measured by Remote PhotoPlethysmoGraphy (rPPG) in stable illumination and noise-controlled environments such as indoors. However, heart rate measure in automotive scene is still faced with several challenges since the lighting illumination in the cab often changes dramatically. To address such issues, a novel method named Illumination Variation Robust Remote-PhotoPlethysmoGraphy (Ivrr-PPG) is proposed for monitoring the heart rate of drivers during on-road driving. The prototype is based on a commercial off-the-shelf imaging system, which includes a monochrome camera with 940 nm narrowband NIR filter and two 940 nm NIR active light sources to collect real-time video of drivers. Based on a dichromatic model, the core idea of our method is to model the non-linear relationship between illumination changing and the rPPG signal. This paper also proposed to use a background region to sense the illumination changing and consequently suppress its impact on the pulse signal. A single-tone sinusoidal signal-based frequency estimation method is then used to compute the heart rate. Experimental results conducted on four different on-road driving scenarios show that the Ivrr-PPG significantly outperforms the state-of-the-art single-channel narrowband NIR algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Published&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 5.332&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;M. Xu, G. Zeng, Y. Song, Y. Cao, Z. Liu, X. He, Ivrr-PPG: an illumination variation robust remote-PPG algorithm for monitoring driver’s heart rate, IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurement, vol. 72, no. 3515510, pp. 1-10. 2023, JCR Q1, IF: 5.332.```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ARTICLE{9507344,
  author={Xu, Ming and Zeng, Guang and Song, Yongjun and Cao, Yue and Liu, Zeyi and He, Xiao},
  journal={IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurement}, 
  title={Ivrr-PPG: an illumination variation robust remote-PPG algorithm for monitoring heart rate of drivers}, 
  year={2023},
  volume={72},
  number={3515510},
  pages={1-10},
  doi={}}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="Journal," /><category term="Rank-5" /><summary type="html">Ivrr-PPG: An Illumination Variation Robust Remote-PPG Algorithm for Monitoring Heart Rate of Drivers</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE TITS [MTSGABL]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/06/LiuZY05/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE TITS [MTSGABL]" /><published>2023-04-06T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-04-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/06/LiuZY05</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/06/LiuZY05/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Real-Time Safety Assessment for Dynamic Systems With Limited Memory and Annotations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/Samlzy/pics/raw/Samlzy-patch-1/LiuZY05.png&quot; alt=&quot;GA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time safety assessment for dynamic systems with limited memory and annotations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time safety assessment of dynamic systems has recently received increasing attention. However, the performance of existing advanced approaches is often negatively affected by realistic requirements such as limited annotations and memory. In this case, how to design reasonable query strategies to select valuable instances and exploit the memory space efficiently is extremely meaningful. This paper proposes a novel memory-triggered submodularity-guided active broad learning approach, termed MTSGABL, to deal with such issues simultaneously. Specifically, the broad learning system is introduced as the basic assessment model to update incrementally. A memory-triggered learning mechanism is then proposed based on the drift detection procedure, which controls the update process to exploit the latest sequential information. Furthermore, a submodularity-guided query strategy is introduced to select a small number of valuable samples sequentially, which is beneficial to alleviate the negative effects of the imbalanced data stream. Numerous comparison and ablation experiments with the realistic JiaoLong deep-sea manned submersible data are conducted to validate its effectiveness. Results show that the proposed approach is superior to the existing typical approaches subject to these constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: In Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 9.551&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCF Rank (中国计算机学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Z. Liu and X. He, “Real-Time Safety Assessment for Dynamic Systems With Limited Memory and Annotations,” IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems, 2023, doi: 10.1109/TITS.2023.3266256.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{liu2023TITS,
  title={Real-Time Safety Assessment for Dynamic Systems With Limited Memory and Annotations},
  author={Liu, Zeyi and He, Xiao},
  journal={IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems},
  year={2023},
  doi={10.1109/TITS.2023.3266256},
  publisher={IEEE}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="Journal," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Real-Time Safety Assessment for Dynamic Systems With Limited Memory and Annotations</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Preprint — [CPRC]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/21/LiuZY02/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preprint — [CPRC]" /><published>2023-03-21T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-03-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/21/LiuZY02</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/21/LiuZY02/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contrastive Preference-Guided Active Learning Approach Based on Ranking Correlation for Chunk-Level Real-Time Safety Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/Samlzy/pics/raw/Samlzy-patch-1/LiuZY02.png&quot; alt=&quot;GA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Contrastive preference-guided active learning approach based on ranking correlation for chunk-level real-time safety assessment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Chunk-level real-time safety assessment is a critical process for identifying and analyzing potential safety hazards in industrial applications. Active learning has been widely rec- ognized as an effective technique for addressing such issues by utilizing small labeled samples to achieve high evaluation performance. However, in real-world scenarios, the performance of query strategies can be significantly impacted by the data environment. Therefore, it is crucial to co-design strategy using different criteria to ensure reliable and stable safety assess- ment results for system operation. In this paper, we propose a contrastive preference-guided active learning approach to tackle chunk-level real-time safety assessment tasks in non- stationary environments. Firstly, we construct negative ranking lists and random lists. Then, we introduce Jeffrey divergence to measure pairwise ranking correlation. By leveraging contrastive preference relationships, we can effectively obtain the value of samples in data chunks with preference aggregation procedures. To verify the effectiveness of the proposed method, we conduct numerous experiments using realistic data from the JiaoLong deep-sea manned submersible. The results demonstrate that our approach outperforms most existing advanced methods in terms of performance stability and accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Under Review&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="preprint," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Contrastive Preference-Guided Active Learning Approach Based on Ranking Correlation for Chunk-Level Real-Time Safety Assessment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE TCST [MCAL]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/14/LiuZY04/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE TCST [MCAL]" /><published>2023-02-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-02-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/14/LiuZY04</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/14/LiuZY04/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fault Diagnosis of Rotating Machinery With Limited Expert Interaction: A Multi-criteria Active Learning Approach Based on Broad Learning System&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/Samlzy/pics/raw/Samlzy-patch-1/MCAL.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;GA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Fault diagnosis of rotating machinery with limited expert interaction: a multi-criteria active learning approach based on broad learning system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Recently, research on the fault diagnosis of rotating machinery, especially for the compound or unknown cases, has drawn increasing attention. Some advanced learning-based approaches have achieved good fault diagnosis performance to some degree. However, in practical applications, how to utilize prior knowledge as fully as possible for fault diagnosis with constraints of limited expert interaction remains an open issue. In this brief, a fault diagnosis methodology of rotating machinery with limited expert interaction is proposed. With related feature extraction techniques, a novel multicriteria active learning (MCAL) query strategy is designed to select the relatively valuable samples for annotation. In addition, the broad learning system (BLS) is exploited to achieve fast incrementally updating or retrain procedures with high diagnostic accuracy in different diagnosis scenarios. Several experiments are conducted on a real-world rotating machinery fault diagnosis (RMFD) experimental platform. Compared with other existing advanced approaches, the diagnosis performance of the proposal shows high stability and flexibility. The annotation cost of experts is also significantly reduced, which makes the proposal more suitable for dealing with practical problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Published&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 5.418&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Z. Liu, J. Zhang, X. He, Q. Zhang, G. Sun, D.-H. Zhou, “Fault diagnosis of rotating machinery with limited expert interaction: A multicriteria active learning approach based on broad learning system” IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 2023, doi: 10.1109/TCST.2022.3200214.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ARTICLE{9869794,
  author={Liu, Zeyi and Zhang, Jingfei and He, Xiao and Zhang, Qinghua and Sun, Guoxi and Zhou, Donghua},
  journal={IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology},
  title={Fault Diagnosis of Rotating Machinery With Limited Expert Interaction: A Multicriteria Active Learning Approach Based on Broad Learning System},
  year={2023},
  volume={31},
  number={2},
  pages={953-960},
  doi={10.1109/TCST.2022.3200214}}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="Journal," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Fault Diagnosis of Rotating Machinery With Limited Expert Interaction: A Multi-criteria Active Learning Approach Based on Broad Learning System</summary></entry></feed>