<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-04-18T21:08:01+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Zeyi Liu</title><subtitle>Personal Acadamic Homepage</subtitle><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><entry><title type="html">SAFEPROCESS-2023 [CADM]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/15/LiuZYC01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SAFEPROCESS-2023 [CADM]" /><published>2023-04-15T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-04-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/15/LiuZYC01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/15/LiuZYC01/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Real-time Safety Assessment of Dynamic Systems in Non-stationary Environments: A Review of Methods and Techniques&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time safety assessment of dynamic systems in non-stationary environments: a review of methods and techniques&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;CAA Symposium on Fault Detection, Supervision, and Safety for Technical Processes (SAFEPROCESS), 2023&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time safety assessment (RTSA) of dynamic systems is a critical task that has significant implications for various fields such as industrial and transportation applications, especially in non-stationary environments. However, the absence of a comprehensive review of real-time safety assessment methods in non-stationary environments impedes the progress and refinement of related methods. In this paper, a review of methods and techniques for RTSA tasks in non-stationary environments is provided. Specifically, the background and significance of RTSA approaches in non-stationary environments are firstly highlighted.We then present a problem description that covers the definition, classification, and main challenges. We review recent developments in related technologies such as online active learning, online semi-supervised learning, online transfer learning, and online anomaly detection. Finally, we discuss future outlooks and potential directions for further research. Our review aims to provide a comprehensive and up-to-date overview of real-time safety assessment methods in non-stationary environments, which can serve as a valuable resource for researchers and practitioners in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Under Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compendex&lt;/strong&gt;: EI Compendex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="preprint," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Real-time Safety Assessment of Dynamic Systems in Non-stationary Environments: A Review of Methods and Techniques</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE-TIM [Ivrr-PPG]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/13/XuM-01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE-TIM [Ivrr-PPG]" /><published>2023-04-13T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-04-13T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/13/XuM-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/13/XuM-01/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ivrr-PPG: An Illumination Variation Robust Remote-PPG Algorithm for Monitoring Heart Rate of Drivers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Ivrr-PPG: an illumination variation robust remote-PPG algorithm for monitoring heart rate of drivers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Heart rate can be accurately measured by Remote PhotoPlethysmoGraphy (rPPG) in stable illumination and noise-controlled environments such as indoors. However, heart rate measure in automotive scene is still faced with several challenges since the lighting illumination in the cab often changes dramatically. To address such issues, a novel method named Illumination Variation Robust Remote-PhotoPlethysmoGraphy (Ivrr-PPG) is proposed for monitoring the heart rate of drivers during on-road driving. The prototype is based on a commercial off-the-shelf imaging system, which includes a monochrome camera with 940 nm narrowband NIR filter and two 940 nm NIR active light sources to collect real-time video of drivers. Based on a dichromatic model, the core idea of our method is to model the non-linear relationship between illumination changing and the rPPG signal. This paper also proposed to use a background region to sense the illumination changing and consequently suppress its impact on the pulse signal. A single-tone sinusoidal signal-based frequency estimation method is then used to compute the heart rate. Experimental results conducted on four different on-road driving scenarios show that the Ivrr-PPG significantly outperforms the state-of-the-art single-channel narrowband NIR algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: In Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 5.332&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;M. Xu, G. Zeng, Y. Song, Y. Cao, Z. Liu and X. He, &quot;Ivrr-PPG: An Illumination Variation Robust Remote-PPG Algorithm for Monitoring Heart Rate of Drivers,&quot; in IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurement, to be published.```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ARTICLE{9507344,
  author={Xu, Ming and Zeng, Guang and Song, Yongjun and Cao, Yue and Liu, Zeyi and He, Xiao},
  journal={IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurement}, 
  title={Ivrr-PPG: an illumination variation robust remote-PPG algorithm for monitoring heart rate of drivers}, 
  year={2023},
  volume={},
  number={},
  pages={1-10},
  doi={}}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="paper," /><category term="Rank-5" /><summary type="html">Ivrr-PPG: An Illumination Variation Robust Remote-PPG Algorithm for Monitoring Heart Rate of Drivers</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE-TITS [MTSGABL]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/06/LiuZY05/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE-TITS [MTSGABL]" /><published>2023-04-06T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-04-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/06/LiuZY05</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/04/06/LiuZY05/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Real-Time Safety Assessment for Dynamic Systems With Limited Memory and Annotations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time safety assessment for dynamic systems with limited memory and annotations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time safety assessment of dynamic systems has recently received increasing attention. However, the performance of existing advanced approaches is often negatively affected by realistic requirements such as limited annotations and memory. In this case, how to design reasonable query strategies to select valuable instances and exploit the memory space efficiently is extremely meaningful. This paper proposes a novel memory-triggered submodularity-guided active broad learning approach, termed MTSGABL, to deal with such issues simultaneously. Specifically, the broad learning system is introduced as the basic assessment model to update incrementally. A memory-triggered learning mechanism is then proposed based on the drift detection procedure, which controls the update process to exploit the latest sequential information. Furthermore, a submodularity-guided query strategy is introduced to select a small number of valuable samples sequentially, which is beneficial to alleviate the negative effects of the imbalanced data stream. Numerous comparison and ablation experiments with the realistic JiaoLong deep-sea manned submersible data are conducted to validate its effectiveness. Results show that the proposed approach is superior to the existing typical approaches subject to these constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: In Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 9.551&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCF Rank (中国计算机学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Z. Liu and X. He, “Real-Time Safety Assessment for Dynamic Systems With Limited Memory and Annotations,” IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems, 2023, doi: 10.1109/TITS.2023.3266256.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{liu2023TITS,
  title={Real-Time Safety Assessment for Dynamic Systems With Limited Memory and Annotations},
  author={Liu, Zeyi and He, Xiao},
  journal={IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems},
  year={2023},
  doi={10.1109/TITS.2023.3266256},
  publisher={IEEE}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="paper," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Real-Time Safety Assessment for Dynamic Systems With Limited Memory and Annotations</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE-TASE [CPRC]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/21/LiuZY02/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE-TASE [CPRC]" /><published>2023-03-21T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-03-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/21/LiuZY02</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/21/LiuZY02/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contrastive Preference-Guided Active Learning Approach Based on Ranking Correlation for Chunk-Level Real-Time Safety Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Contrastive preference-guided active learning approach based on ranking correlation for chunk-level real-time safety assessment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Chunk-level real-time safety assessment is a critical process for identifying and analyzing potential safety hazards in industrial applications. Active learning has been widely recognized as an effective technique for addressing such issues by utilizing small labeled samples to achieve high evaluation performance. However, in real-world scenarios, the performance of querying strategies can be significantly impacted by the data environment. Therefore, it is crucial to co-design strategy using different criteria to ensure reliable and stable safety assessment results for system operation. In this paper, we propose a contrastive preference-guided active learning approach to tackle chunk-level real-time safety assessment tasks in non-stationary environments. Firstly, we construct negative ranking lists and random lists. Then, we introduce Jeffrey divergence to measure pairwise ranking correlation. By leveraging contrastive preference relationships, we can effectively obtain the value of samples in data chunks with preference aggregation procedures. To verify the effectiveness of the proposed method, we conduct numerous experiments using realistic data from the JiaoLong deep-sea manned submersible. The results demonstrate that our approach outperforms most existing advanced methods in terms of performance stability and accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Under Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 6.636&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A+&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCF Rank (中国计算机学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: B&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="preprint," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Contrastive Preference-Guided Active Learning Approach Based on Ranking Correlation for Chunk-Level Real-Time Safety Assessment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE-TNNLS [DSLS]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/01/LiuZY07/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE-TNNLS [DSLS]" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/01/LiuZY07</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/01/LiuZY07/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dynamic Submodular-based Learning Strategy in Imbalanced Drifting Streams for Real-time Safety Assessment in Nonstationary Environments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Dynamic submodular-based learning strategy in imbalanced drifting streams for real-time safety assessment in nonstationary environments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: The design of real-time safety assessment approaches in nonstationary environments is meaningful to reduce the possibility of significant losses. However, several challenging problems are needed to be well considered. The performance of existing approaches will be negatively affected in the settings of imbalanced drifting streams. In this case, the model design with the incremental update should also be explored. Furthermore, the query strategy should also be well designed. This paper investigates a dynamic submodular-based learning strategy to address such issues. Specifically, an efficient incremental update procedure is designed with the structure of the broad learning system, which is beneficial to the detection of concept drift. Furthermore, a novel dynamic submodular-based annotation with activation interval strategy is proposed to select valuable samples in imbalanced drifting streams. The lower bound of annotation value is also proven theoretically with a novel drift adaption mechanism. Numerous experiments are conducted with the realistic data of JiaoLong deep-sea manned submersible. The experimental results show that the proposed approach can achieve better assessment accuracy than typical existing approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Major Revision&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 14.255&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCF Rank (中国计算机学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: B&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="preprint," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Dynamic Submodular-based Learning Strategy in Imbalanced Drifting Streams for Real-time Safety Assessment in Nonstationary Environments</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE-TCST [MCAL]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/14/LiuZY04/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE-TCST [MCAL]" /><published>2023-02-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-02-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/14/LiuZY04</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/14/LiuZY04/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fault Diagnosis of Rotating Machinery With Limited Expert Interaction: A Multi-criteria Active Learning Approach Based on Broad Learning System&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Fault diagnosis of rotating machinery with limited expert interaction: a multi-criteria active learning approach based on broad learning system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Recently, research on the fault diagnosis of rotating machinery, especially for the compound or unknown cases, has drawn increasing attention. Some advanced learning-based approaches have achieved good fault diagnosis performance to some degree. However, in practical applications, how to utilize prior knowledge as fully as possible for fault diagnosis with constraints of limited expert interaction remains an open issue. In this brief, a fault diagnosis methodology of rotating machinery with limited expert interaction is proposed. With related feature extraction techniques, a novel multicriteria active learning (MCAL) query strategy is designed to select the relatively valuable samples for annotation. In addition, the broad learning system (BLS) is exploited to achieve fast incrementally updating or retrain procedures with high diagnostic accuracy in different diagnosis scenarios. Several experiments are conducted on a real-world rotating machinery fault diagnosis (RMFD) experimental platform. Compared with other existing advanced approaches, the diagnosis performance of the proposal shows high stability and flexibility. The annotation cost of experts is also significantly reduced, which makes the proposal more suitable for dealing with practical problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Published&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 5.418&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Z. Liu, J. Zhang, X. He, Q. Zhang, G. Sun, D.-H. Zhou, “Fault diagnosis of rotating machinery with limited expert interaction: A multicriteria active learning approach based on broad learning system” IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 2023, doi: 10.1109/TCST.2022.3200214.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ARTICLE{9869794,
  author={Liu, Zeyi and Zhang, Jingfei and He, Xiao and Zhang, Qinghua and Sun, Guoxi and Zhou, Donghua},
  journal={IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology},
  title={Fault Diagnosis of Rotating Machinery With Limited Expert Interaction: A Multicriteria Active Learning Approach Based on Broad Learning System},
  year={2023},
  volume={31},
  number={2},
  pages={953-960},
  doi={10.1109/TCST.2022.3200214}}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="paper," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Fault Diagnosis of Rotating Machinery With Limited Expert Interaction: A Multi-criteria Active Learning Approach Based on Broad Learning System</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">JiaoLong DSMS Datasets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/01/JiaoLong_Dataset/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JiaoLong DSMS Datasets" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/01/JiaoLong_Dataset</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/01/JiaoLong_Dataset/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;JiaoLong Deep-Sea Manned Submersible datasets (Life Support System)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data used in this paper was collected and provided from the National Deep Sea Center in Qingdao, Shandong, China. The initial data is collected in the \(151^{st}\) exploration task for the JiaoLong DSMS on March \(19^{th}\), 2017.
The form of data is the multi-variate time series with around 11 features for about 3 hours. The sub-system of JiaoLong DSMS such as life support system is selected to analyze. Our purpose is to assess the safety level, such as safe level and unsafe level, for the tested data stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seven variables of the life support system represent the real-time monitoring indicators, including oxygen (\(O_2\)) concentration in the cabin, carbon dioxide (\(CO_2\)) concentration in the cabin, cabin pressure (Pa), cabin humidity, and cabin temperature (\(^\circ\)C). In addition, backup 2 and backup 3 are also considered, representing the oxygen concentration of another set of oxygen sensors and the carbon dioxide concentration of another set of carbon dioxide sensors, respectively. Two settings of oxygen and carbon dioxide sensors are set up in the cabin as a backup to monitor the oxygen and carbon dioxide concentration at any time.  Hence, the monitoring data of backup 2 and backup 3 are the values of another set of oxygen and carbon dioxide sensors. Moreover, four settings of other external monitoring variables containing salinity, temperature, depth, and speed are selected. The monitoring data is sourced from the value of the conductivity temperature depth (CTD) sensor installed outside the JiaoLong DSMS, which monitors the real-time seawater salinity, temperature, depth, and the speed of ascending and descending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the experiment, the JiaoLong DSMS gradually descended from the shore to around 3000 meters. It is worth noting that the used labels are derived from the records of real voyage logs obtained in JiaoLong DSMS. The total number of samples is \(64138\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details, please refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/liuzy0708/JiaolongDSMS_datasets&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Github Repository&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="dataset" /><summary type="html">JiaoLong Deep-Sea Manned Submersible datasets (Life Support System)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE-TCYB [DMI-LS]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/01/LiuZY08/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE-TCYB [DMI-LS]" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/01/LiuZY08</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/01/LiuZY08/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dynamic Model Interpretation-Guided Online Active Learning Scheme for Real-Time Safety Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Dynamic model interpretation-guided online active learning scheme for real-time safety assessmen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Chunk-based real-time safety assessment of dynamic systems is of great significance for the timely discovery of industrial risks and reduction of losses. However, existing methods have certain limitations in dealing with such issues, especially in non-stationary environments. Generally, potential concept drift needs to be detected interpretively, which is inevitable in many cases. The incremental learning scheme should also be well considered. In this paper, the dynamic model interpretation-guided online active learning scheme, termed DMI-LS, is proposed. Specifically, the model update strategy with chunk data is designed based on the implementation of the broad learning system. A novel query strategy is then investigated to consider the ranking preference difference, which relies on the interpretation generated by the explainable artificial intelligence method. Several experiments based on the JiaoLong deep-sea manned submersible data are conducted to verify the effects of the proposed DMI-LS. The results show that it outperforms the other advanced existing approaches with different settings in most scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Major Revision&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 19.118&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCF Rank (中国计算机学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: B&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="preprint," /><category term="Rank-1" /><summary type="html">Dynamic Model Interpretation-Guided Online Active Learning Scheme for Real-Time Safety Assessment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE-TII [MPPOS-RVFL]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/15/HanPY01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE-TII [MPPOS-RVFL]" /><published>2023-01-15T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/15/HanPY01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/15/HanPY01/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Minority Pseudo-label Prioritized Online Semi-supervised Random Vector Functional Link Network Approach for Industrial Real-time Fault Diagnosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: A minority pseudo-label prioritized online semi-supervised random vector functional link network approach for industrial real-time fault diagnosis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Industrial Informatics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Industrial real-time fault diagnosis is vital to ensure efficient and safe production. In the literature, existing methods usually do not systematically consider some realistic constraints in dealing with the above problem, such as real-time model update, sample imbalance, and high cost of labeling. In this paper, a minority pseudo-label prioritized online semi-supervised random vector functional link network approach, termed MPPOS-RVFL, is proposed to cope with the above issue. Specifically, the pseudo-labeling technique is introduced to reduce the negative impact of the imbalanced data stream. In this context, the minority pseudo-label prioritized approach is designed to enhance the model’s ability to identify unlabeled minority samples. Several experiments with the Tennessee Eastman process are conducted to verify the practicality of MPPOS-RVFL. The results demonstrate that the proposed method outperforms the existing advanced approaches in accuracy and time consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Under Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCR&lt;/strong&gt;: Q1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact Factor&lt;/strong&gt; (2021): 11.648&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAA Rank (中国自动化学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: A+&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCF Rank (中国计算机学会评级)&lt;/strong&gt;: C&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="preprint," /><category term="Rank-2" /><summary type="html">A Minority Pseudo-label Prioritized Online Semi-supervised Random Vector Functional Link Network Approach for Industrial Real-time Fault Diagnosis</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EAI-SCUBE [CADM]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/01/HuS01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EAI-SCUBE [CADM]" /><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/01/HuS01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/01/HuS01/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CADM: Confusion Model-based Detection Method for Real-drift in Chunk Data Stream&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: CADM: Confusion model for real-drift detection in chunk data streams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of 13th EAI International Conference on Sensor Systems and Software&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Concept drift detection has attracted considerable attention due to its importance in many real-world applications such as health monitoring and fault diagnosis. Conventionally, most advanced approaches will be of poor performance when the evaluation criteria of the environment has changed (i.e. concept drift), either can only detect and adapt to virtual drift. In this paper, we propose a new approach to detect real-drift in the chunk data stream with limited annotations based on concept confusion. When a new data chunk arrives, we use both real labels and pseudo labels to update the model after prediction and drift detection. In this context, the model will be confused and yields prediction difference once drift occurs. We then adopt cosine similarity to measure the difference. And an adaptive threshold method is proposed to find the abnormal value. Experiments show that our method has a low false alarm rate and false negative rate with the utilization of different classifiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current State&lt;/strong&gt;: Accepted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compendex&lt;/strong&gt;: EI Compendex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;S. Hu, Z. Liu, X. He. CADM: Confusion Model-based Detection Method for Real-drift in Chunk Data Stream, Proceedings of 13th EAI International Conference on Sensor Systems and Software, 2022, in Dec., Dalian, Liaoning, China.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{hu2023cadm,
  title={CADM: Confusion Model-based Detection Method for Real-drift in Chunk Data Stream},
  author={Hu, Songqiao and Liu, Zeyi and He, Xiao},
  journal={arXiv preprint arXiv:2303.16906},
  year={2023}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Zeyi Liu</name><email>liuzy21@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn</email></author><category term="paper," /><category term="Rank-2" /><summary type="html">CADM: Confusion Model-based Detection Method for Real-drift in Chunk Data Stream</summary></entry></feed>